United Airlines announcing the arrival of Flight 9435 from Beijing.
聯合航空公司的從北京飛來的 9435號航班即將降落
Customer service representative, report to Gate C42.
客戶服務代表，請到C42門報導
All visitors to the US should line up at booths one through 15.
所有旅客排好隊從15號通道到一號亭
Please have your I-94 forms filled out.
請填寫一下I-94表格（入境/ 出境記錄）
- What's the purpose of your visit? - What is the purpose of your visit?
- 您此行的目的是什麼？
What is the purpose of your visit? Business or pleasure?
您此行的目的是什麼？ 商務旅行還是觀光？
Just visiting. Shopping?
觀光…購物？
Au plaisir.
觀光
- Pleasure. - Business.
- 觀光 - 商務旅行
How long will you be staying?
您打算逗留多久？
Could I see your return ticket?
能出示一下您的回程機票嗎？
- What's the purpose of your visit? - Business or pleasure?
- 您此行的目的是什麼？ - 商務旅行還是觀光？
Enjoy your stay. Next.
祝您此行愉快，下一位
Please have your passports, immigration forms, I-94,
請出示您的護照和I-94 表格
and customs declarations ready to hand to the inspector.
準備好您的報關證明以備核查
- Stand by. He's fishing. - Copy that.
- 準備，有情況 - 收到
See this bunch of Mickey Mouse sweatshirts?
看見那些穿米老鼠T恤的人了嗎？
That's the tour from China, connecting to Orlando.
中國來的旅遊團，去奧蘭多的
When was the last time you saw Chinese tourists
你什麼時候見到中國的觀光者
on their way to Disney World without any cameras?
去迪斯尼而不帶相機的？
Possible forged documents on 1 0 and 1 1.
10號和11號通道發現有偽造文件嫌疑的旅客
Sir. Sir. Passport.
先生，先生，護照
Thank you.
謝謝
Welcome, Mr. Navorski.
歡迎，納沃斯基先生。
Purpose of your visit?
您此行的目的是？
Business or pleasure?
商務旅行還是觀光？
Sir, I have an IBIS hit on six.
先生，6號台發現一個護照有問題的
No!
不！
Mr. Navorski, please follow me.
納沃斯基先生，請跟我來
...flight number 746 from Montreal
…從蒙特利爾來的746航班
must proceed to US Immigration before claiming their luggage.
認領行李之前請先到移民登記處
All right, Mr. Navorski, we'd like you to wait here, please.
好吧，納沃斯基先生 請在這裡等候
Next, please.
下一位
What are you doing in the United States, Mr. Navorski?
您到美國做什麼，納沃斯基先生？
Yellow taxicab, please.
請幫我叫出租車
Take me to Ramada Inn,
去拉瑪達酒店
1 61 Lexington.
列剋星敦街161號
Staying at the Ramada Inn?
您要住在拉瑪達酒店？
Keep the change.
不用找零了
Do you know anyone in New York?
在紐約有熟人嗎？
Yes.
是的
- Who? - Yes.
- 誰？ - 是的
- No, do you know anyone in New York?
- 你在紐約有認識的人嗎？
- Who? - Yes.
- 誰？ - 是的
1 61 Lexington.
列剋星敦街161號
OK, Mr. Navorski, I need to see your return ticket, please.
好吧，納沃斯基先生，請出示您的回程機票
No, your return ticket. Your...
不，您的回程機票…
- Oh... Yes. - Ah.
- 哦…是的 - 啊
This is just a standard procedure.
只是例行公事
I'm going to need the passport also.
還需要護照
Oh... OK.
哦，好的
- No, no. - Thank you.
- 不，不 - 謝謝你
Mr. Navorski.
納沃斯基先生。
That. Passport.
那個，護照
That.
那個
Mr. Navorski? Sorry to keep you waiting.
納沃斯基先生？ 抱歉讓您久等了
I'm Frank Dixon, Director of Customs and Border Protection here at JFK.
我是弗蘭克 迪克遜，機場海關及邊境保護局的主任
I help people with their immigration problems.
我負責處理與移民相關的事務
We're looking for an interpreter for you.
我們正在幫您找翻譯
How are we doing on that? Do we have an interpreter?
怎麼樣了？翻譯找到了？
But I understand that you speak a little English.
我知道您懂一點英語
- Yes. - You do?
- 是的 - 真的嗎？
I hope you don't mind if I eat while we talk. I've a bit of bad news.
希望您不介意我邊吃邊說，我有些壞消息
Your country has suspended all traveling privileges
您的國家已經暫停了其簽發的護照上
on passports issued by your government.
所有的出行特權
And our State Department has revoked the visa
敝國國務院已經註銷了您的簽證
that was going to allow you to enter the US.
您將不被允許進入美國
That's it in a nutshell, basically.
簡而言之，基本上就這麼回事
While you were in the air there was a military coup in your country.
您還在飛機上的時候，您的國家發生了軍事政變
Most of the dead were members of the Presidential Guard.
死者多是總統衛隊的成員
They were attacked in the middle of the night.
他們在半夜受到攻擊,發生了猛烈的交火
They got it all on GHN, I think.
我想新聞已經播過了
There were few civilian casualties. I'm sure your family's fine.
也有少數平民傷亡，我相信您的家人沒出事
Mr. Navorski, your country was annexed from the inside.
納沃斯基先生,您的國家內部合併了
The Republic of Krakozhia is under new leadership.
克羅西亞共和國已經更換了領導人
Krakozhia. Krakozhia
克羅西亞…克羅西亞
- Krakozhia. - Right. I don't think he gets it.
- 克羅西亞 - 是的，我覺得他沒聽懂
Er... Let me... OK. Look.
呃…我…好吧
Imagine that these potato chips are Krakozhia.
把這些薯片當做克多西亞
Kra-kozhia.
克羅西亞
- Kra-kozhia. - Yes.
- 克羅西亞 - 是的
- Krakozhia. - OK.
- 好吧
Er... So the potato chips are Krakozhia.
呃…這些薯片就是克羅西亞
- And this apple... - Big Apple. Big Apple.
- 這個蘋果… - 大蘋果（紐約的別名）
...Big Apple represents the Liberty Rebels.
…大蘋果代表自由民變
OK?
明白嗎？
No more Krakozhia! OK?
沒有克羅西亞了！
New government. Revolution. You understand?
新政府，革命，你懂嗎？
All the flights in and out of your country have been suspended.
所有進出裡面國家的航班都無限期推遲了
The new government has sealed all borders, so your visa's no longer valid.
新政府封鎖了邊境，您的護照無效了
So, currently you are a citizen of nowhere.
現在您變成無主之人了
Now, we can't process you new papers
在美國政府給您的國家重新進行外交分類之前
until the US recognizes your country's new diplomatic reclassification.
我們不能給您簽發任何文件
You don't qualify for asylum, refugee status,
您也不能申請庇護，避難
temporary protective status, humanitarian parole,
臨時保護, 也不能給您簽發人道入境證明
or non-immigration work travel. You don't qualify for any of these.
和非移民工作，旅遊簽證 這些你都不能享受
You are at this time simply...
您現在是……
...unacceptable. - Unacceptable.
…不受歡迎 - 不受歡迎
Big Apple tour includes Brooklyn Bridge, Empire State, Broadway show Cats.
紐約游包括布魯克林大橋，帝國大廈 百老匯音樂劇《貓》
I got more bad news for you. Cats has closed.
我還有壞消息，《貓》已經停演了
OK. OK.
好，好
Now I go New York City. Thank you.
那我現在去紐約，謝謝
No, Mr. Navorski. I cannot allow you to enter the United States at this time.
不，納沃斯基先生，您此刻不能進入美國國境
- Krakozhia. - We can't allow you to go home either.
- 克羅西亞 - 也不能允許您回國
You don't really have a home. Technically it doesn't exist.
從理論上來講，您也沒有祖國了
It's like a Twilight Zone. Do you get that show over there?
有點像《陰陽魔界》裡面的情況 你們國家播這部劇集了嗎？
Talking Tina, Zanti Misfits.
天娜和贊蒂米斯菲特
Zanti Misfits was Outer Limits, sir.
贊蒂米斯菲特是《外部極限》的人物，先生
Really? It's not important.
真的嗎？這無關緊要
Where do I buy the Nike shoes?
在哪裡可以買耐克鞋？
OK, Mr. Navorski, come here.
納沃斯基先生，到這兒來
Here's my dilemma, Mr. Navorski.
現在情況比較複雜，納沃斯基先生
You have no right to enter the US and I have no right to detain you.
您沒有權利進入美國 我也沒有權利扣留您
You have fallen through a crack in the system.
您掉進了這個體系的一個漏洞裡面了
- I am crack. - Yes. Until we get this sorted out,
- 我，漏洞 - 是的，在我們妥善處理好之前
I will allow you to enter the International Transit Lounge.
我可以允許您進入國際過境休息廳
I'm going to sign a release form that is going to make you a free man.
我將給你簽發一張許可證，允許你自由出入
- Free? - Free. Free.
- 自由？ - 自由，自由
Free to go anywhere you like in the International Transit Lounge.
您可以在國際過境休息廳範圍內自由活動
- OK? - OK.
- 行嗎？ - 可以
OK.
好
Uncle Sam will have this sorted out by tomorrow,
您的事情明天就能解決
and welcome to the United States. Almost.
歡迎來到美國
- Thank you. - OK. All right.
- 謝謝 - 好的
Thanks, Judge.
謝謝，賈吉
Announcing the arrival of flight 76 from Singapore Airlines.
新加坡航空公司的76號航班即將降落
Now, Mr. Navorski.
現在，納沃斯基先生
Mr. Navorski. Mr. Navorski.
納沃斯基先生…納沃斯基先生
This is the International Transit Lounge.
這裡就是國際過境休息廳
You are free to wait here. These are food vouchers.
你可以在這裡等候，這是餐券
You can use them in the Food Court. Your Krakozhian money is no good here.
你可以去那邊的餐廳買東西 你的克羅西亞貨幣在這裡是沒用的
This is a 1 5-minute, prepaid calling card.
這是1張預付15分鐘話費的電話卡
You may call home, if you like.
你可以打電話回家
This, in case we need to contact you, is a pager.
這是呼機，我們用它聯絡你
You must keep this with you at all times.
你必須隨身攜帶
Here is an ID badge for you to get into CBP. Beyond those doors...
這是給你的一張出入海關及邊境保護局的身份卡 那些門的外面…
Mr. Navorski. I'm going to need you to look at me.
納沃斯基先生，你看著我
Beyond those doors is American soil.
那些門的外面就是美國領土
Mr. Dixon wants me to make it clear
迪克遜先生要我說清楚
that you are not to enter through those doors.
你不能走出那些門
You are not to leave this building. America is closed.
你不能離開這棟樓，美國對你關閉了
America closed.
美國關閉了
What I do?
我該做什麼？
There's only one thing you can do here, Mr. Navorski.
納沃斯基先生，只有一件事
Shop.
購物
Passengers of flight 854 New York/Warsaw...
從紐約飛往華沙的854號航班的旅客…
...the international community tries to secure a peaceful resolution.
…國際社會正在尋求和平的解決方法
The populace has to wonder if they will ever find political stability,
民眾不得不考慮他們是否能獲得政治上的穩定
or find the leadership to secure their place on the world stage.
他們的領導人是否能在世界舞台上站穩腳跟
And next this hour, looking to buy a 90-foot yacht?
想買90英呎的遊船嗎？
...taken hostage. We're hearing that the Vice President has been killed
…被劫持…副總統
along with four cabinet members, 1 3 injured soldiers and 20 civilians.
以及四位內閣成員被殺 13名士兵和20位平民受傷
By dawn, rebel leaders had surrounded the state houses.
黎明時候，叛軍領導人已經包圍政府大樓
In a symbolic gesture, the national flag of Krakozhia was torn down
作為標誌的克羅西亞國旗
from the Presidential Palace and the parliament building.
已經從總統官邸和議會大廈撤下
Please. Please.
幫幫忙，幫幫忙
Television.
電視
Passenger Chen Wan-Shiu and Liu Tao-Jing,
旅客程宛秀，劉淘金
please come to podium to pick up your boarding passes.
請到總台領取你們的登機證
This just in. Last night a military coup overthrew the government of Krakozhia.
最新消息，昨晚一場軍事政變推翻了克羅西亞政府
Bombing and gunfire were heard through the night.
槍炮聲整晚不歇
Although details are unclear,
雖然具體情況不明
we are told that President Vagobagin and his aides have been taken hostage.
據悉瓦果巴爾金總統和他的住手們已經被劫持
Bonjour, monsieur. You are a Red Carpet Club member?
您好，先生，您是紅毯俱樂部的會員嗎？
I need to see your boarding pass and club card, sir.
請出示您的登機卡和會員證
I'm sorry, sir. This is a private lounge.
抱歉，先生，這裡是私人候機處
The public lounge is downstairs.
公眾候機處在樓下
The tiniest nation in the region has been shaken by another uprising.
這個該地區最小的國家又一次受到衝擊
Krakozhia has been involved in civil war throughout the late '80s and '90s
克羅西亞80年代末期和90年代
as it has tried to transition from Communist rule.
在從共產主義轉型的過程中一直內戰不斷
- Watch it! - Please.
- 小心！ - 幫幫我
Please, telephone? Telephone?
幫幫忙，電話？ 電話？
Please. Please.
幫幫忙…幫幫忙
For security reasons, please keep your luggage with you at all times.
請看管好隨身攜帶的行李
Unattended luggage will be removed for inspection and may be destroyed.
無人看管的行李會送去檢查甚至銷毀
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, you broke my bag!
哦，天哪，他弄壞了我的箱子！
I got this in Paris. This is my favorite bag.
是我在巴黎買的，我最喜歡的箱子
I can't believe you just broke my bag! Mom, Dad! He broke my bag!
真不敢相信，爸爸，他弄壞了我的箱子！
- Food document. - Excuse me. Stop it. Stop it.
- 餐券 - 對不起，住手，住手
Do you have an appointment?
你有預約嗎？
I don't let anyone to look at my trash without an appointment.
如果沒有預約，我不允許任何人看我的垃圾
I have an opening next Tuesday.
我下星期二有空
Tuesday. Tuesday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Tuesday.
星期二…星期二 星期一，星期二，星期一，星期二
It will be good time for you to come back and get lost.
那時候你再來找你的東西
OK, goodbye. Sorry.
再見，抱歉
Tuesday.
星期二
Don't shoot!
別開槍！
She sleeps 12, Frank. Has a 120-volt generator, wet bar, gas range.
她有12張床位，弗蘭克 有一個120伏特的發電機，一個小吧檯，瓦斯爐
She looks amazing.
太迷人了
She's my pot of gold at the end of the rainbow.
簡直是我的夢中情人
She's a beautiful boat and I hope you get her soon.
這船真漂亮，您趕緊買下吧
- You've earned her. - Thank you, Frank.
- 您掙的夠多的了 - 謝謝，弗蘭克
- You have. - Actually, I bought her yesterday.
- 說真的 - 實際上，我昨天就買了
Come on. Congratulations!
恭喜你啦！
I'm nominating you to take my place.
我已經推薦你接替我
You will assume the duties of acting Field Commissioner
你可以開始履行代理地區特派員的職責
until you get approval from Washington.
就等華府的任命書了
Really? I don't know what to say.
真的嗎？ 都不知道該說什麼了
- Jesus. Richard, is this real? - It's real, Frank, it's real.
- 老天。理查德，是真的嗎？ - 是真的，弗蘭克，千真萬確
Don't pretend to be surprised.
別假裝大吃一驚的樣子了
You've been waiting for me to retire or drop dead for years now.
你等我退休或者出意外已經不止一年兩年了
No, I haven't been waiting for you to retire.
不，我並沒等你退休
That's all right, Frank.
好吧，弗蘭克
My retirement will become official the day you get sworn in.
你一上任我就正式退休
- You've waited a long time for this. - I have.
- 你久等了 - 是啊
Just be careful about the inspection process.
小心稽核人員
I will. I've been here for 1 7 years...
我會的，我在這裡工作已經17年了…
We're talking about the Field Commissioner position.
我們說的是地區特派員
People are going to look to you for leadership, to set an example.
大家指望你做個好領導，給他們以身作則
What are you saying?
你說什麼？
I'm saying the job is yours to lose.
我是說這回這位子跑不出你的手心了
Ship the Colombians off to asylum hearings,
把那些哥倫比亞人送到收容所 查一下那些中國人的背景，準備遣返
and call the parents of those kids from Long Island.
給長島來的那些孩子的父母打電話
Tell them it was a bad idea to let them go to Jamaica.
告訴他們讓他們去牙買加不是個好主意
Come on, let's go. South America and Madrid are on the tarmac.
好了，南美還有馬德里來的飛機已經降落了
I want them out of here in half an hour.
半個小時把他們搞定
Mr. Thurman.
瑟曼先生
There's a man walking around the terminal in a bathrobe.
這個人穿著睡衣晃悠
I know, sir. You put him there.
我知道，先生，你把他放那裡的
Welcome to the United States.
歡迎來到美國
Next!
下一位！
I need visa.
我要簽證
Where's your green form? I can't do anything without it.
你的綠色表格呢？沒它不行
Go to the wall.
到牆那邊去
Next!
下一位！
Sir.
先生
The light green form.
是淡綠色的
Light green.
淡綠
Mr. Navorski, you cannot get into New York without a visa.
納沃斯基先生，沒有簽證去不了紐約
You cannot get a visa without a passport,
沒有護照就拿不到簽證
and you cannot get a new passport without a country.
沒有一個國家就拿不到新護照
There's nothing we can do for you here.
我們沒什麼可以幫你的
I give you light green.
我給了你淡綠色的表格
I'm sorry, but you've wasted an entire day.
抱歉，你在浪費時間
At this time you are simply...
你現在是…
- Unacceptable. - Yes.
- 不受歡迎的 - 是的
Unacceptable.
不受歡迎
Why is he still here?
他怎麼還在？
You released him, sir. You put him there.
你把他放了，送到那裡去的
Why doesn't he walk out the doors? Why doesn't he try to escape?
他怎麼不溜出門去？ 他怎麼不逃跑？
- Sir, you told him to wait. - I didn't think he'd actually do it.
- 先生，你讓他等的 - 我沒指望他真的這麼等
I mean, he's in a crack. Who the hell waits in a crack?
我是說他現在麻煩大了，換了誰也不會等下去的
No news from the State Department, but we can deport him in a few days.
國務院沒有新的消息 也許我們過幾天就可以遣返他了
Yeah, it could be a few days. It could be a week, two weeks, a month.
是啊，也許幾天，也許一個星期 兩個星期，也許一個月
Who knows what this guy is thinking, what gulag he escaped from.
誰知道這傢伙怎麼想的，也許是從集中營出來的
Next!
下一位！
Everything he does comes back to me.
他所做的每一件事情都要向我匯報
- You want him back in the holding cell? - No, I'll show him the door.
- 您不想把他關起來？ - 不，我讓他自己進去
Hello.
你好
- Do you have an appointment? - Yes. 9.30.
- 你有預約嗎？ - 是的，9月30號
Food document, trash. Tuesday.
餐券，垃圾，星期二
Tuesday. I hate the Tuesday.
星期二，我討厭星期二
Excuse me.
對不起
Airports are tricky places, Mr. Navorski.
機場是個需要技巧的地方，納沃斯基先生
I'm about to tell you something.
我有點事情告訴你
Something you can never repeat to anyone.
你可不能告訴別人
Do you understand? It's a secret.
明白嗎？ 這是秘密
- Secret? - Yes, a secret.
- 秘密？ - 是的，秘密
At 1 2 o'clock today, the guards at those doors will leave their posts
今天12點，門口的警衛換班的時候
and their replacements are going to be five minutes late.
接他們班的警衛會來遲5分鐘
Late five minutes.
遲5分鐘
Yes. Late five minutes. At 1 2 o'clock. Just today. Just this once.
是的，遲5分鐘，12點，今天，就一次
No one is going to be watching those doors.
門口沒有警衛
- And no one will be watching you. - So, America not closed.
- 沒人會看你 - 那麼美國沒有關閉
No.
沒有
America, for five minutes, is open.
美國，對你開放5分鐘
Have a nice life, Mr. Navorski.
祝你順心，納沃斯基先生
Catch and release. It's simple. Sometimes you land a small fish.
抓了又放，很簡單，有時候，你放了一條小魚
You unhook him and place him back in the water.
你把它放回水裡
You set him free so that somebody else can have the pleasure of catching him.
你放了它，別人就可以享受釣魚的樂趣了
All right, here we go.
好了，開始了
OK. Call them off.
叫他們走開
Johnson, clear the doors.
強生，離開門口
All right. Go.
好了，走開啊
Get out of there. All right, there's the door.
好了，門就在那裡
All right.
好吧
Here we go. Now where is he?
他在哪裡？
- There he is. - No, that's not him.
- 在那兒 - 不，不是他
There he is.
在那兒
All right, Viktor.
好啦，維克多
Here we go.
可以走了
What's so complicated? Exit, Viktor.
怎麼這麼複雜？ 走啊，維克多
Come on. In a few minutes, you'll be somebody else's problem.
拜託，過幾分鐘，你就是別人的麻煩了
He wants to make sure nobody's watching.
他在看有沒有人注意他
I told him nobody would be watching.
我告訴他沒人看著他的
Come on. All right, here we go.
快點啊，出去啊
- Call the Airport Police. - He's on his way.
- 打電話給機場警察 - 已經派人去了
Excuse me.
借過
You got it. There we go.
就這樣
He's got to get a running start, I guess.
我猜他是不是要助跑啊
Just leave. Just leave.
走啊，還猶豫什麼
Leave. Leave.
快走
What are you doing? Why is he kneeling? Is he praying?
他在幹嗎？ 跪下來幹嗎，祈禱嗎？
No. He's tying his shoelace.
不，他在繫鞋帶
Come on, leave.
拜託，快走吧
Get the cameras.
鏡頭移開
Where is he? Where is he?
人呢？ 人哪裡去了？
- To the left of here. - No. He was at the door.
- 往左 - 不，原來是在門口的
- Just go a little left. - All right. All right.
- 在往左一點 - 好了，好了
I wait.
我等
What are you looking at? Go back to work. Thank you.
有什麼好看的？ 回去工作吧，謝謝
Oh, God. Oh, shit.
哦，見鬼
- This belong you? - Thank you.
- 這是你的？ - 謝謝
Oh, shit.
該死
See? Wet floor.
看見了？ 小心濕滑
That you.
說的就是你
I'm so late.
我太趕時間了
Buenos Aires. I can't remember the gate.
布宜諾斯艾利斯 我不記得是哪個門了
Gate 24.
24號門
- You sure? - Yes.
- 是嗎？ - 是的
Thanks.
謝謝
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士們先生們…
Wait.
等等
For you. Payless Shoes.
給你的，免費鞋
Second floor. Sensible heels.
二樓，穿著很舒服
- Hi, baby. - Come here, you.
- 嗨，寶貝 - 到這兒來
I think he's CIA. The CIA put him here to spy on us.
我說他是CIA CIA讓他來監視我們
You don't know what you're talking about. He doesn't speak English.
胡扯，他都不會說英語
If he could learn to speak, this guy.
他會學的
He can't speak English, how could he have a meeting with a beautiful woman?
如果他不會英語，怎麼能和一個漂亮的小妞會面？
A flight attendant.
一個空姐
- So, she's CIA, too? - No.
- 那她也是CIA？ - 不是
She look like a Russian. KGB. She gave him heel of her shoes.
她像是俄國人，是克格勃，她給他鞋後跟
And he gave her a piece of the paper.
他給了她一張紙
- Was it microfilm? - A coupon from Payless Shoes.
- 是微縮膠卷嗎？ - 是一張免費鞋的贈券
Must be some kind of the code.
也許是某種密碼
You been spending too much time inhaling them cleaning products.
我看你是清潔劑吸多了
I'm warning you guys. You watch yourself.
我警告你們，他在監視我們
This guy is here for a reason. And I think that reason is us.
這傢伙來是有目的的，是衝我們來的
Excuse me, buddy.
對不起
What's going on?
怎麼了？
It's Navorski. He's figured out the quarters.
是納沃斯基，他找到了掙錢的方法
Good afternoon. Welcome to Burger King. May I take your order?
下午好，歡迎光臨漢堡王，您需要點什麼？
Keep the change.
不用找了
Excuse me.
對不起
OK, go. Go.
走吧，走開
Good boy. Thank you.
好孩子，謝謝
Bye-bye.
再見
Welcome to Burger King. May I take your...
歡迎光臨漢堡王，您需要點…
"Crisis. Crisis in Krakozhia. "
"危機，克羅西亞危機"
Now that heavy fighting has subsided
目前劇烈的交火已經平息
and both sides have dug in for the long winter ahead,
雙方都在深挖溝壕以抵禦漫長的寒冬
it's clear that the future of Krakozhia may be in doubt for some time to come.
顯然克羅西亞的未來局勢 在一段時間內還不會趨於明朗
Meanwhile, the people of Krakozhia suffer the consequences.
同時，克羅西亞的人民正遭受煎熬
"And food... in... "
"食物…在…"
...have caused food and energy shortages.
…在克羅西亞已經出現
"... in Krakozhia. "
"…食品和能源短缺"
"The story of Broadway is the... "
"百老匯的故事…"
"The cast of comedy hit Friends
"喜劇"…"朋友"…《老友記》的演員，
which is set in New York. "
該劇所講述的故事發生在紐約
Friends.
朋友
Due to the heavy snowfall, all flights have been cancelled...
所有航班因為暴雪取消
"Wayne Newton is 61 today. "
"韋恩 牛頓今天61歲生日"
"It's a miracle. "
"真是奇蹟"
"Korean conjoined twins separated today in Maine. "
"韓國連體嬰兒今天在緬因州成功分離"
"Chances of survival 50-50."
"存活的機會是50%"
50-50.
50%
Next.
下一位
Let me ask you something, Mr. Navorski.
有件事情問你，納沃斯基先生
Why do you wait here every day when there's nothing I can do for you?
我說過沒什麼可以為你做的 你怎麼還是每天浪費兩個小時在我這裡？
Your new visa will not arrive until your country is recognized by the US.
只有你的國家被美國承認以後，才能給你簽證
You have two stamp.
你有兩個章
One red, one green.
一個紅，一個綠
- So? - I have chance to go New York, 50-50.
- 那又怎麼樣？ - 那我去紐約的機會就是百分之五十
Yes. That's a beautiful way to look at it, but America doesn't work that way.
這樣看問題很樂觀，但美國的情況不是這樣
As acting Field Commissioner, I've created a new position here at JFK.
作為地區特派員，我在機場新設了一個崗位
Transportation Liaison for Passenger Assistance.
客戶援助運輸聯絡員
Sir, what will that person do?
先生，那傢伙要干什麼？
Thank you. I'll take it from here.
謝謝，交給我吧
I'm Transportation Liaison in charge of Passenger Assistance.
我是運輸聯絡員負責旅客援助
No carts, no quarters. No quarters, no food.
沒推車，就沒硬幣 沒硬幣，就沒食物
It'll be days before he goes through the doors in violation of section 2.1 4
用不了多久他就會違反2條14款走出那門了
Then he's somebody else's problem.
那就不關我們的事情了
Why don't we tag him in violation of section 2.1 4 now?
為什麼我們現在不指控他違反2條14款？
Then ship him to detention.
然後送他去羈留所
He has to break the law by leaving.
得讓他違法才能趕走他
I won't lie, particularly to get rid of somebody like him.
我不會說謊，特別是為了趕走他這樣的傢伙
- Sorry, buddy. - Honey!
- 對不起，夥計 - 親愛的！
Put it down. Put it down.
放下，放下
Put it down.
放下
You try to take my mop. You try to take my floor.
你想拿我的拖把，拖我的地板
It's my job. Stay off my floor. Stay away from my mop.
這是我的工作，走開，別碰我的拖把
- Food. - If you touch it again, I kill you.
- 食物 - 你再碰，我就殺了你
Hey. I'm Enrique Cruz.
嘿，我是恩裡剋剋魯茲
We need to talk.
我們談談
- I want to make a deal with you. - What deal?
- 我跟你做筆交易 - 什麼交易？
I need information on CBP Officer Torres.
我需要邊境保護局官員桃莉絲的一些信息
You feed me information about her and I'll feed you.
你給我她的信息，我給你吃的
- What do you want know? - You see her every day.
- 你想知道什麼？ - 你每天都見到她
I want to know what makes her knees weak.
我想知道怎樣使她兩腿發軟
What makes her blood boil and her body tingle.
熱血沸騰，渾身癢癢
She's a wild stallion and you'll help me break her.
她是匹野馬，你幫我馴服她
I'm...
我…
I'm her man of mystery.
我是她的仰慕者
- Officer Torres is wild stallion? - Her name is Delores.
- 桃莉絲小姐是野馬？ - 她叫德洛蕾絲
You help me to win her heart and you'll never go hungry again.
你幫我贏得她的芳心，你就不會挨餓了
- I do this. - Really? Promise?
- 成交 - 真的？ 你保證？
- Yes. - OK. Thank you.
- 是的 - 好，謝謝
What mean, "wild stallion"?
你說，"野馬"是什麼意思？
Officer Torres. My friend say you are stallion.
桃莉絲小姐，我朋友說你是馬
Mr. Navorski.
納沃斯基先生
- A what? - Stallion, like a horse.
- 什麼？ - 馬，地上跑的馬
Stand behind the yellow line.
站到黃線後面去
- It's beautiful horse. - Who said that?
- 美麗的馬 - 誰說的？
- My friend drive the food. - Mr. Navorski, behind the yellow line.
- 我朋友是送飯的 - 納沃斯基先生，退到黃線後面去
- I will help once it's your turn. - I'll get light green.
- 輪到你我再招呼你 - 我去拿表格
- Light green form. - I'll be back.
- 淡綠色的 - 馬上回來
She say one thing.
她說了一件事情
- Very important. - What? What did she tell you?
- 很重要 - 什麼？ 她說了什麼？
Something wrong with the salmon?
鮭魚不好吃嗎？
Need gorchitsa.
要加點「gorchitsa」
What?
什麼？
Mustard. Mustard?
芥末，芥末？
- Mustard? - Yes. Please.
- 芥末？ - 是的，是的
Thank you.
謝謝
Officer Torres, you like the films?
桃莉絲小姐，你喜歡看電影嗎？
- Movies? - Not so much.
- 電影？ - 一般
- The Rockettes? - Can't afford it.
- 火箭？ - 買不起
- What do you like? - Conventions.
- 那你喜歡什麼？ - 聚會
Conventions. What is?
聚會，這是什麼？
- Conventions?
- 聚會？
This is like secret place you go?
是你去的什麼秘密地方嗎？
She go to these conventions dressed as Yeoman Rand.
她打扮成姚曼蘭的樣子去參加聚會
- Yeoman Rand. - She's a Trekkie.
- 姚曼蘭 - 她是星艦迷
Favorite episode is Doomsday Machine.
最喜歡的一集是「末日機器」
Now, listen, Viktor.
聽著，維克多
You can ask her something that is very important.
你幫我問問一句很重要的話
- OK. - Look...
- 好 - 聽著…
- I wait. - Enjoy your visit.
- 我等 - 祝您此行愉快
Next.
下一位
- Officer Torres. - Mr. Navorski.
- 桃莉絲小姐 - 納沃斯基先生
You have choose.
你會選擇
Man with money or man with love?
有錢的人還是有愛的人？
What is choose?
選什麼？
She had a boyfriend?
她有男朋友了？
For how long? Two years?
多久了？ 兩年？
What happened?
怎麼了？
He chit.
他「七邊」
- What? - He chit.
- 什麼？ - 他「七邊」
Eat shit?
「吃便」？
He chit. He chit. He chit.
他「七邊」…他「七邊」
- Repeat exactly what she said. - He chit. She catch him. So...
- 你把她的話完整地重複一遍 - 他「七邊」…她抓到他，所以…
- He cheats. - Yes.
- 他欺騙，欺騙她 - 是的
What we call krushkach. We say krushkach.
我們叫做「krushkach」…「krushkach」
One man, two womans.
一個男人，兩個女人
So. Mm.
所以
Crowded, you know.
太擠了
OK. He cheats.
嗯，他欺騙她
- You say "cheats". - He chit.
- 跟我說「欺騙」 - 「七邊」
- No, "cheat". - Enrique.
不，「欺騙」
You, no chit.
你，不能「七邊」
- No cheat. - No chit.
- 不欺騙 - 不「七邊」
No. I won't cheat.
我不會騙她的
She's a nice girl. She won't take your chitting.
她是個好女孩，不會上你的當的
Next.
下一位
Officer Torres. Have you been ever in the love?
桃莉絲小姐，你有沒有愛過？
Enough, Viktor. Who is it?
夠了，維克多…是誰？
Who's telling you to ask me these things?
誰讓你來問我這些問題的？
It's a man of misery.
是一個「神必人」
Misery?
「神必」？
- Mystery? - No, no. Misery. Man of misery.
- 神秘？ - 不，不 「神必」，「神必人」
He's so sick. He's so in love.
他愛得不可救藥
But what did she say?
她說什麼？
She did say, "Next! Next!"
她說，"下一位！ 下一位！"
And now she say, "Please. Please come. "
還說"請過來"
That's... Wait.
是…等等
- I coming now. - No, wait. Viktor.
- 我來了 - 不，等等。 維克多
Viktor, just tell me more.
維克多，再跟我講多點
I coming. I coming.
我來了，我來了
Please, please.
借過，借過
Beeper went off. Started beeping. So, I grab. I come.
傳呼機響，我，來
We have an idea.
我們有了個主意
Would you like something to eat?
要吃點東西嗎？
No. No food. I stuffed.
不，食物，不要，我，飽了
OK. All right.
好吧
Thank you.
謝謝
So, Mr. Navorski, I have some very good news for you.
納沃斯基先生 我有好消息要告訴你
What?
什麼？
I've figured out a way to get you out of this airport.
我想出讓你出這個機場的辦法了
How?
什麼辦法？
Well, we have laws here that protect aliens
我們有些法律保護那些
who have a credible fear of returning to their own country.
非常害怕回到自己國家的外國人
If we can establish this fear with you,
如果我們能看出你的這種恐懼
then the CBP will be forced to begin Expedited Removal Procedures,
那麼邊境保護局就必須加快處理
to bring you to an immigration judge and let you plead your case for asylum.
送你去移民法官那裡申請避難
- Asylum? - Mm-hm, asylum.
- 避難？ - 嗯，避難
Unfortunately, the courts are so backed up with asylum cases
很不幸，申請此類的案件非常多
that the soonest you'd get before a judge would be six months from now.
你起碼要等上六個月才能見到法官
Yes, and we would have no choice
是的，我們別無選擇
but to let you go for those six months. It's the law. You'd be released.
只能在這六個月時間內讓你自由 這就是法律，我們會釋放你
You would be free to wait in New York until your court date.
你可以在紐約自由地等到上庭的那天
But, believe it or not, most people never show up before the judge.
不管你信不信，很多人從此就消失了
- So I go New York City? - Uh-huh.
- 那我可以去紐約？ - 嗯
You can go to New York City tonight.
今晚就可以去紐約？
But, you only get to go if we can establish a credible fear.
但首先，得讓我們看到你的恐懼
- Fear? - Mm-hm, fear.
- 恐懼？ - 是的，恐懼
- Fear.
- 恐懼
From what?
恐懼什麼？
That's the best part.
這就是最有意思的地方
It doesn't matter what you're afraid of. It's all the same to Uncle Sam.
你怕什麼並不重要，美國政府不關心
So I'm going to ask you one question,
所以，我下面要問你一個問題
if you give me the correct answer, I can get you out of this airport tonight.
如果你回答正確，我就可以送你出機場
So, I answer one question.
我，回答一個問題
Go to New York City. Tonight.
去紐約，今晚
- Tonight.
- 今晚
- OK.
- 好的
All right.
好吧
Do you, at this time, have any fear of returning to your own country?
你，現在是不是害怕回到你的國家？
No.
不
OK. Let me try it again.
重新來一遍
- Your country's at war. - Yes. War.
- 你的國家在打仗 - 是的，打仗
There are men in the streets with guns. Political persecution.
街上都是拿著槍的人，政治迫害
- Yes. It's terrible. - Yeah, it's horrible.
- 很可怕 - 是的，很恐怖
And God only knows what could happen.
天知道會發生什麼事情
Innocent people are torn from their beds.
無辜的民眾被從被窩裡拖出來扔進監獄
On Tuesdays. I hate Tuesdays.
星期二，我討厭星期二
So you're afraid.
所以你很害怕
- From what? - Krakozhia.
- 怕什麼？ - 克羅西亞
You're afraid of Krakozhia.
你害怕克羅西亞
Krakozhia?
克羅西亞？
No, I am not afraid from Krakozhia. I'm a little afraid of this room.
不，我不怕克羅西亞 我倒是有點怕這間房間
I'm talking about bombs. I'm talking about human dignity.
我說的是炸彈，人的尊嚴
Human rights.
人權
Viktor, please don't be afraid to tell me you're afraid of Krakozhia.
維克多，告訴我你害怕回克羅西亞 說吧，別怕
Is home. I am not afraid from my home.
那是家，我不害怕家
So? I go to New York City now?
我可以去紐約了？
- No. - No?
- 不行 - 不行？
OK.
好吧
- I'm afraid from ghosts. - Thanks very much.
- 我怕鬼 - 非常感謝
- I'm afraid from Dracula. - Thanks a lot.
- 害怕吸血鬼伯爵 - 多謝
I'm afraid from Wolfmens, afraid from sharks.
害怕狼人，害怕鯊魚
Thanks a lot.
謝謝
Damn.
該死
- Why you do this? - Nobody read the sign in America.
- 你為什麼這麼做？ - 在美國，沒人看警告牌
This is the only fun I have.
這是我唯一的樂趣
A barbecue? That's why I'm not going to see you?
野餐？因為這個你不能來見我？
Let me get this straight. I change my schedule to meet you.
我跟你說，我跟別人換了班
I take four back-to-back flights,
我連飛了四趟
fly 27 hours straight literally around the world,
不間斷飛了27個小時，幾乎繞地球一圈了
and now you tell me you're going to spend July 4th with your wife?
現在你告訴我你要和你妻子一起過國慶？
The woman hates fireworks.
你妻子不喜歡焰火
Don't lie to me, OK?
別說謊了？
I know for a fact you took her to Rome last weekend.
我知道你上個週末帶她去羅馬了
Because you flew United, Max.
因為你們坐的聯航的飛機，麥克斯
South African Airlines passenger Sharif Al-Calala,
南美航空公司的乘客
please come to the main ticket counter.
請到檢票處
You make a habit out of listening to other people's conversations?
你喜歡偷聽別人說話？
No, I try to call home.
不，我是在想打電話回家
So then...
那麼…
- You know why men are such assholes? - No.
- 你知道為什麼男人都是混蛋嗎？ - 不知道
Because they're all liars.
因為男人都是騙子
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
等等，等等
Wet floor.
地板滑
Please. Don't be hurt.
別受傷了
How can I not be? He's married.
我怎麼會這樣？ 他已經結婚了
One man. Two womens. Crowded.
一個男人，兩個女人，太擁擠了
You want to know what the worst part is?
你知道最壞的是什麼地方嗎？
I never asked him to leave his wife. I encouraged him to get counseling.
我從來沒讓他離開他妻子，還鼓勵他去諮詢
What kind of sick person am I?
我怎麼這麼變態？
I'm rooting for the home team.
居然還支持他們
I just wish the sex wasn't so amazing.
真希望做愛不是那麼迷人就好了
- So amazing. - Bye-bye.
- 那麼迷人 - 再見
You know... sometimes in the mornings,
有時候，早上…
I just stare at him over room service.
我看著他
Watch him do the crossword puzzle.
看著他做拼字遊戲
I start to think that maybe... maybe this could happen.
我開始想，也許有可能…
That we belong together.
我倆是天生一對
This... man... has you.
那…男人…有了你
Why he need... puzzle?
為什麼還…玩拼字遊戲？
This is my problem.
這是我的問題
I always see men the way I want to see them.
我總是一廂情願地看男人
Do I know you from someplace?
我們以前見過嗎？
Sensible heels. Payless Shoes. Second floor.
免費鞋，穿著舒適，二樓
Oh...
哦…
You headed for home?
你是回家？
Er... No, no. I am...
呃…不，不是，我…
I am delayed a long time.
我的航班已經延誤了很長時間了
I hate it when they delay flights. What do you do?
我也不喜歡航班延誤，你做什麼的？
I go from one building to another building.
從一棟建築跑到另一棟建築
I have beeper.
我有呼機
Oh, contractors. You guys travel as much as we do.
哦，建築承包商，你和我們一樣常年在外面旅行
Sorry about that. Thank you very much.
抱歉，多謝了
What's "BH"?
你叫什麼？
In English...
用英語講…
Viktor Navorski.
維克多·納沃斯基
- In English, Amelia Warren. - Amelia Warren?
- 我叫艾米利亞·華倫 - 艾米利亞·華倫？
- Nice to meet you. - You, too.
- 幸會
Nice to see you again.
很高興再次見到你
You like Italian food?
你喜歡意大利菜嗎？
I know, it's late and you've probably got other plans,
我知道很晚了，也許你有其他計劃
but if you'd like to grab some dinner, we can run right out and catch a cab.
如果你願意和我一起出去吃點東西 我們可以出去坐計程車
I know a place that has the greatest cannelloni.
我知道一個地方，那裡的肉卷特別棒
Erm...
呃…
No, I... I can't.
不，我…不行
- You married? - No.
- 你結婚了？ - 沒
- Girlfriend?
- 有女朋友了？
I... I can't go out... with you.
我…我不能…和你出去
God. I am so... I'm so sorry.
天哪，…非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
對不起
I must come off like a complete nut job or something.
我一定是瘋了
- No. - I didn't want to eat alone.
- 不 - 我只是不想一個人吃飯
Wet floor. Wet floor.
地板，小心，滑
- I... - You don't have to explain.
- 我… - 不用解釋了
No, I... Please, I...
不，我…請你，我…
Wheelchair to gate A-five.
請送一副輪椅到A5門
Nadia.
娜蒂亞
In New York restaurant, what cost is cantaloni?
在紐約，意大利肉卷要多少錢？
I don't know. Maybe 1 5 bucks.
不知道，也許15元
- Dollars? - 20.
- 美元？ - 20
Two people, 40.
兩個人，40
Two people, 40 dollars.
兩個人，40美元
I... I... help you?
我…我…幫你？
I'm so sorry, sir. The position has already been filled.
抱歉，先生，我們不缺人了
- Do you live nearby? - Yes. Gate 67.
- 你住在附近？ - 是的，67門
Because we are very particular about punctual... Did you say Gate 67?
因為我們需要員工守時…你是說67號門？
Gate 67.
67號門
You got to be kidding.
你肯定是在開玩笑
You got to help me help you. I don't see a Social Security number...
你得先幫我，我才能幫你，你沒有社保號碼…
...mailing address, even a phone number.
…通訊地址，甚至電話號碼也沒有
Telephone? You need? I get. I get. I get phone.
電話？ 你要電話？ 我有，我有電話
I get... I get phone.
我有…有電話
451 -1 226.
451-1226
All right. When's the best time to reach you?
好吧，什麼時候方便聯絡你？
Now?
現在？
- Hello? - Hi, Mr. Navorski.
- 喂？ - 你好，納沃斯基先生
Yes, this is Viktor Navorski. Who calls?
是的，我是維克多·納沃斯基，請問哪位？
It's Cliff from the Discovery Store.
我是探索頻道專賣店的，克利夫
Cliff. Hello.
克利夫，你好
- How's it going? - Good.
- 你好嗎？ - 很好
- Is this a good time? - Yes, I wait for your call all day.
- 現在談方便嗎？ - 是的，我等了你一整天
Well, I got to tell you that the position's been filled.
我得告訴你，我們已經請到人了
Yeah, so could you please go sit someplace else?
那你能不能坐到其他地方去？
- I go to bathroom now. - That'd be good.
- 我去洗手間 - 很好
- All right. - Thank you.
- 好吧 - 謝謝
OK.
好的
Who is this?
這傢伙是誰？
- Who are you? - It's no one.
- 你是什麼人？ - 不認識
There's no one here for two weeks. This isn't one of my guys.
這裡已經兩個禮拜沒人了，不是我的人
Look at this cornicing. This is good work.
看啊，他手藝不錯
Must be Harry's crew. You with Harry's crew?
也許還是哈里的人，你是哈里的人嗎？
Does Harry think he's running this job?
哈里以為自己是老大嗎？
- I go now. - Go? Go where?
- 我走了 - 走？ 去哪裡？
- Gate 67. - 67?
- 67號門 - 67？
We're ten months away from 67.
離67號門起碼還有10個月
He's got to be Harry's. If he's not mine and he's not yours...
如果不是你我的人，一定是哈里的…
Harry's trying to make me look bad.
哈里想讓我出醜
I've got to slow him down before he gets to 67.
我等在他弄到67號門之前，讓他慢下來
- What's your name? - Viktor Navorski.
- 你叫什麼？ - 維克多·納沃斯基
Pull him off Harry's crew, put him on mine.
把他從哈里那裡挖出來，到我隊裡來
You start 6.30 Monday morning.
星期一早上6點半開工
You give me job?
你給我工作？
6.30, yes... Boss.
6點半，好的…老闆
We have lobster ravioli from Alitalia.
有意大利航空的龍蝦餃子
We have caviar from Russian Aeroflot.
俄羅斯航空的魚子醬
OK. Just bring it.
好，端上來吧
- Hey, Viktor. - Hello, all.
- 嘿，維克多 - 大家好
Look. The man without a country.
瞧啊，沒有祖國的人
Come on in. Welcome.
來吧，歡迎
- I see this. - You did well.
- 我看見這個 - 你幹得不壞
Have a seat.
坐吧
- Here? - Here.
- 這兒？ - 這兒
Come on, sit down.
來吧，坐下
- Who invited him? - I did. We needed a fourth, right?
- 誰請他的？ - 我，我們三缺一，不是嗎？
- I'm not going to play with him. - Gupta, relax, would you?
- 我不跟他玩 - 古普塔，別緊張？
- He isn't a spy. - How do you know?
- 他不是間諜 - 你怎麼知道？
He could be recording everything we say. A wire in his shirt.
他會錄下我們的對話，也許身上有竊聽器
A microphone up in his ass.
屁眼裡面有麥克風
- I'm not going to lose my job. - Fine.
- 我會丟了工作的 - 好吧
- What if we x-rayed him? - Yes.
- 那我們給他照X光如何？ - 好
Close your eyes.
閉上眼睛
- OK. So you are clean. - Good. Let's play cards.
- 好吧，你沒問題 - 很好，玩牌吧
I will have money. But... Friday.
我沒有錢，但是…星期五…
Don't worry about it. We play for unclaimed items from the Lost and Found.
別擔心，我們賭的是失物招領處無人認領的東西
You'll be amazed at what people leave at airports. Come.
你決不會想到人們的機場會丟些什麼下來，來吧
I have two nines and two nines.
我有兩個9還有兩個9
Four nines. Thank you.
4個9，謝謝
- Careful. - Watch out.
- 小心 - 注意點
- We have a question for you. - Yeah, we're just curious.
- 我有個問題問你 - 我們只是好奇
What is in the can?
罐子裡面是什麼？
- This? - We saw the x-ray.
- 這個？ - 我們在照X光的時候看見了
We know there's no nuts in there.
我們知道里面不是什麼罐頭食品
What is in there?
到底是什麼？
This is jazz.
是爵士
- Jazz? - Jazz, yes.
- 爵士？ - 爵士，是的
- Yes.
- 是的
You sure it's jazz in there? It might be the blues.
是爵士嗎？我還說是藍調呢
- Or salsa. - Maybe it's Stevie Wonder.
- 或者是騷沙 - 也許是史提夫汪達
- No, no, is jazz. - OK, guys. OK.
- 不，不，是爵士 - 好吧，好吧
For tonight's grand prize, we have...
今天的大獎是…
Show them, Gupta.
給他們看看，古普塔
I found this upstairs.
我在樓上撿到的
Virgin Air, first class lounge.
維京航空公司，頭等艙候機處
There you go.
來了
And... they belong to?
這是…是誰的？
Cher.
雪兒
Cher?
雪兒？
As in... Cher?
那個歌星…雪兒？
Yeah. Cher.
是的，雪兒
I checked it out. There were witnesses.
我問過了，有目擊者
Those are Cher's panties.
是雪兒的內褲
- Ready? - Hurry up.
- 準備好了？ - 快點
So, will we share the panties?
我們分了這條內褲？
- No, no, no. - Not if I win.
- 不，不 - 誰贏了就是誰的
- Come on. - Wait a second.
- 來吧 - 等等
United Airlines flight number 801 to Narita
聯航飛往成田機場的801航班
is now announcing final boarding.
最後一次登機
"You can't. That is mine. "
"不行，這是我的"
Viktor?
維克多？
Well, hi.
嗨
Please.
我來撿
- How are you? - Good.
-你好嗎？ -很好
Man.
老天
I am so sorry about what happened last time, asking you out like that.
上回的事我很抱歉 竟然那樣子約你出去
I'm so used to guys trying to grab my ass at 30,000 feet
三萬英呎高空有人捏我屁股 我老早就習以為常了
that when I meet somebody that doesn't, I don't know how to react.
當我遇見個不這麼做的人 反而不知道該怎樣反應
- Let's just start over. - Yes, OK.
-我們重新來過吧 -好的
- Are you coming or going? - I don't know. Both.
-你是入境還是出境？ -不知道，都算吧
Tell me about it.
跟我說說看
Napoleon?
拿破崙？
Yeah. I read a lot of history books. They're long and cheap.
對，我看很多歷史書籍 故事長，價格又便宜
Like 1 200 pages for $9.99. You can't beat that.
1200頁才賣9.99美元，太便宜了
- But Napoleon? - Yeah. He's one of my favorites.
-可是拿破崙？ -對，他是我最喜愛的人物之一
- You know what saved Napoleon's life? - No.
-你知道是什麼救了拿破崙一命嗎？ -不知道
- His ego. - Ego?
-他的自大 -自大？
Yes.
沒錯
After he loses the Battle of Waterloo,
在他滑鐵盧一役慘敗後
Napoleon isolates himself on the tiny island of Saint Helena.
拿破崙將自己孤立在聖海倫娜小島上
No one knows exactly what happens next,
沒人確切知道後來發生什麼事
but the version I like goes like this:
但我喜歡的版本是這樣的
He's very depressed and decides to take his own life.
他非常沮喪，決定了結自己的性命
But Napoleon believes himself to be of such superhuman strength
但拿破崙深信自己 要有過於常人的勇氣
that he takes six times the amount of poison needed to do the job.
所以服下自殺所需毒藥六倍的劑量
His stomach is so full up with poison that his body rejects it,
他的胃裝滿了毒藥，他的身體產生排斥
and he doesn't die.
而他卻沒死
See? Ego. Saved his life.
瞧？ 自大救了他一命
Maybe he need glasses.
也許他需要眼鏡
- Glasses? - Yes. To read words on bottle.
-眼鏡？ -對，好看清瓶子上的字
Poison.
毒藥
It's funny you should say that.
你那麼說真是有趣
Rumor has it that Napoleon was farsighted.
謠傳拿破崙有遠視
- There you go.
-說的好
I think we're rewriting history right here.
我認為我們正在此重寫歷史
Why don't we talk about it over lunch?
我們何不邊吃午餐邊聊呢？
Oh, my God, I can't believe it. I just asked you out again.
老天，我不敢相信 我剛剛又約你了
I just did it again.
我剛剛又做了
I'm so... Just stay away from me, Viktor, OK?
我好… 維克多，離我遠一點，好嗎？
I'm sick. I don't have the ability to be alone for five seconds.
我有病，我沒辦法獨處五秒鐘
OK.
好吧
- OK, what? - OK.
-什麼好吧？ -好吧
Lunch... with you.
與你…共進午餐
- You'll have lunch with me? - Yes.
-你要與我共進午餐？ -對
You're not running for a flight or...?
你不用趕搭飛機或者…？
I wait.
我在等
- It's me. - You. Yes.
-找我的 -你的，沒錯
I'm sorry. I just got paged.
對不起，我剛收到訊息
You work?
要上班了嗎？
- No. - Ah.
不是
Three of you. Crowded.
三人行太擠了
Stay away from me, Viktor.
離我遠一點，維克多
I'm... I have a serious problem. I'm as bad as Napoleon.
我…我有個嚴重的問題 我跟拿破崙一樣壞
I just keep ingesting these poisonous men until I make myself sick.
我一直在消化這些有毒的男人 直到令我自己生病為止
- You're not sick, Amelia. No. - No?
-你沒病，艾米利亞，沒有 -沒有嗎？
No. You're a little... farsighted.
沒有，你是有點…遠視
- I have to go. - I have to stay.
-我得走了 -我得留下
- Story of my life. - Me, too.
-我的人生便是如此 -我也是
Your CBP inspection's in three days.
再過三天，你那些邊境局的檢查員
The FBI and Homeland Security will tour the airport,
FBI和國安局的人將巡視機場
spend two hours observing these offices before your interview process begins.
在和你的訪談開始之前 會先花兩小時巡視這些辦公室
How much does Navorski make?
納沃斯基賺多少？
Sir?
長官？
How much does he make? How much are they paying him?
他賺多少？ 他們付他多少薪水？
They're paying him cash under the table.
他們是私下付他現金的
I know that. How much?
我曉得，多少？
$1 9 an hour.
時薪19美元
Unbelievable. Do you know that's more than I make?
不可思議 你知道那比我賺的還多嗎？
That's New York City construction.
那就是紐約市建築工的價錢
One of my own men came up to me the other day.
前幾天有個員工上來找我
Asked me if I wanted to join the big pool.
問我想不想也下賭注
Look at him.
看看他
Place a bet on when Navorski's going to leave this airport.
在下賭注看看納沃斯基 何時會離開這座機場
Have you heard about this?
你聽說過此事嗎？
I have January 3rd.
我賭1月3日
Bring him in.
帶他進來
Jake, he has no nationality. OK? No country.
傑克，他沒有國籍，懂嗎？ 沒有國家
He's a national security risk, according to my interpretation of Section 2.1 2.
據我對第二條第三款的解釋 他對國家安全是個威脅
I want you to put him in a detention center and run a clearance on him.
我要你把他關進聯邦拘留中心 對他進行審訊
That's all I want.
我只希望能那樣
What about a federal prison?
聯邦監獄如何？
What about another airport?
別的機場如何？
Hello? Hello?
喂？ 喂？
We're detaining so many people, there's no room anywhere.
我們扣留了那麼多人 竟然找不到一處收容他
- Did you try the FBI? - I tried everybody. Nobody'll take him.
-你試過FBI嗎？ -每個人都試過了，沒人願意收容他
You want me to bring him back to the terminal?
要我帶他回候機室嗎？
No. From now on, Navorski lives here.
不要，從現在起，納沃斯基住這裡
The people who are coming here today will be observing me, inspecting me.
今天要來的人將會觀察我、審查我
But most of all they will be looking at the way that this airport is run.
但最重要的是 要看看本機場的運作方式
So let's show them why this is the number-one airport in the United States.
因此讓我們表現給他們看看 為何這裡是全美第一名的機場
We process about 600 planes a day,
我們一天處理六百架班機
with a processing time of 37 minutes per plane,
平均每架班機花費37分鐘
about 60 seconds per passenger...
每位旅客大約是60秒…
...to be brought into the country.
…進入本國
We keep it as clean as possible.
我們儘可能徹底安檢
- What do you import? - Computer software.
-你攜帶了什麼進來？ -電腦軟件
That's a lot of walnuts.
一大堆胡桃呢
Yeah. My mother-in-law loves these things.
對，我岳母喜歡吃這些
Every time I go to Brazil, I bring her back a bag.
我每次去巴西，都會幫她帶一包回來
- Your mother-in-law? - Yeah.
-你的岳母？ -對
Mind if I try one?
介意我試吃一個嗎？
How did you know those weren't for his mother-in-law?
你怎麼知道那些不是要帶給他岳母的？
If he's married, where's his ring?
他如果結婚了，戒指在哪呢？
And if he's divorced, who still talks to their mother-in-law?
如果離了婚，誰還會跟岳母聊天呢？
I'm sorry, but really. No offence to mother-in-laws, but...
抱歉，不過事實如此 無意冒犯岳母，不過…
- Sir. - Yeah.
-長官 -嗯
Sir, we have a situation upstairs.
長官，樓上有狀況
- It'll have to wait. - No. This won't wait.
-那得等一下了 -不行，這事不能等
When the 9.1 2 from Toronto landed, they found four prescriptions without an MPL.
9點12分從多倫多來的班機降落時 他們發現四瓶沒有醫療責任保險的藥
They tried to take the pills away and he went nuts.
他們想把藥拿走，他就發狂了
There he is. We think they're for his father.
他在那裡 我們認為藥是帶給他父親的
Sir, sir, calm down. Put your weapons down.
先生，冷靜，把武器放下
Everybody keep your weapons... All right. We're here to help you.
武器通通收好… 好了，我們是來幫你的
We're here to help you, sir. All right. Give me the knife.
我們是來幫你的，先生 好了，刀子給我
- Where's he from? - Russia.
-他從哪來的？ -俄羅斯
The only interpreter we got is in Newark.
我們唯一的翻譯人員現在在紐華克
- We have to get someone to talk to him. - I have an idea, sir.
-必須找個人來跟他談 -我有個主意，長官
Viktor.
維克多
Oh...
哦…
I need your help.
我需要你幫忙
His name is Milodragovich. He lives near you.
他叫做米洛卓格維奇 住的離你比較近
He may not speak your dialect,
他可能會說你們的方言
but I need you to translate and help me out.
但我需要你幫忙我翻譯
- I help you? Why? - I don't want anybody to get hurt.
-要我幫你？ 為什麼？ -因為我不希望任何人受傷
This guy's very upset.
這傢伙非常生氣
Just calm him down and I'll let you back in the terminal.
讓他冷靜下來，我就讓你回候機室
No. New York. No red stamp. Green. I green.
不，讓我去紐約 別蓋紅色戳章，綠色，我要蓋綠色的
- New York. - OK, yes.
-紐約 -好的，好
- You say yes? - Yes.
-你說好？ -好
- OK. OK, OK, OK. - Stay out!
-好了，好了 -退後！
We have somebody here to talk to you. Somebody to talk to you. Go ahead.
我們找了個人來跟你談 去吧
Stay out!
退後！
So?
怎樣？
OK, tell him in order to export medicines from this country,
好的，告訴他要從本國攜帶藥品
he needs to have the proper form, a Medicinal Purchase License.
必須填寫正式表格 附上購藥許可證
OK? You understand me, Viktor?
好嗎？ 你明白我說的嗎，維克多？
He say he bring the medicine for his father.
他說藥是帶給他父親的
This why he go to Canada. Medicine for father.
所以他才去加拿大替他父親買藥
It doesn't matter.
那不重要
His plane landed in the US. He needs to have the right form.
他的班機降落在美國 他必須有適當的表格
He did not know he need this document.
他不知道需要這種文件
No one say to him he need document form.
沒人跟他說他需要文件表格
I'm saying it to him.
我正在對他說啊
He needs to have the form signed by the hospital who is treating his father.
他需要有治療他父親 醫院簽署的表格
These medicines have to stay in the United States.
這些藥品必須留置在美國境內
They have to stay here.
必須扣留在此
He... He's begging you.
他…他在懇求你
I know. I can see that he's begging.
我知道，我看的出他在求我
I'm sorry, sir.
很抱歉，先生
You'll have to take a flight in the morning. The medicine stays here.
你必須一大早搭飛機離開 藥得留在這裡
I'm sorry.
對不起
Send him down!
制住他！
Thank you, Viktor. Good job. Let's go.
謝謝你，維克多 干的好，我們走吧
Goat.
山羊
- What? - Goat. It medicine is for goat.
-什麼？ -山羊，藥是給山羊用的
- Goat? - Yes. Medicine is for goat. Goat.
-山羊？ -對，藥是給山羊用的，山羊
- He said that? - Yes.
-他那麼說嗎？ -是的
He say...
他說…
We not understand. I not understand "goat".
我們不懂 是我不懂"山羊"
Why? What are you saying? You misunderstood him?
為什麼？ 你在說什麼？ 你聽錯了他的話嗎？
- It's not for his dying father? - No. No.
-不是買給他垂危的父親嗎？ -不是，不是
The... Krakozhia... The name for "father"...
在克羅西亞…"父親"這個字…
sound like "goat".
聽起來很像"山羊"
I make mistake.
是我弄錯了
Why are you doing this, Viktor?
你為何這樣做，維克多？
Medicine is for... goat.
藥是買給…山羊用的
- No, it's not. - Yes.
-不，才不是 -是
- No.
-不是
You read the blue immigration form.
你看過了藍色的表格
- Blue? - Yes. Blue.
-藍色的？ -對，藍色的
- Blue. The blue form.
-藍色的表格
The one that says if it's an animal, he doesn't need the license.
那種表格上說，如果是用於動物身上 就不需要許可證
Then he can bring the drugs in. That's good, Viktor. That's very good.
那他就可以把藥帶進來 利害，維克多，非常利害
Why are you doing this? Huh?
你為何這麼做呢？
You don't know him. You don't know the rules.
你又不認識他，你不懂得規定
Look at me.
看著我
I was going to help you.
我是想幫你
Now I want you to ask him... No, not you.
現在我要你問他… 不，不是聽你說
I want you to ask him. I want to hear him say it.
我要你問他，我要聽見他親口說
I want to hear him say who the medicine is for.
我要聽見他親口說藥是給誰用的
Please. Who the medicine is for.
請說一下藥是給誰用的
Answer him, Mr. Milodragovich. Who are the pills for?
回答他，米洛卓格維奇先生 藥是給誰用的？
OK. The pills stay. He goes. That's it.
好的，藥留下 他走，就這樣
Goat.
山羊
Please. For goat.
拜託，是給山羊用的
Medicine for goat.
藥是給山羊用的
Give him the pills.
藥還他
Medicine...
藥…
Come on now, it's all over.
快走吧，全結束了
He love that goat.
他愛死山羊了
Do you think I need an excuse to put you back in that cell
你以為我需要藉口 才能將你送回那牢裡
to keep you there for five years?
把你關在那兒五年嗎？
You go to war with me, and you go to war with the United States.
你與我為敵，就是與美國為敵
Then you'll know why Krakozhians wait in line for cheap toilet paper
然後你就會懂得為何克羅西亞人 大排長隊等著買廉價衛生紙
while Uncle Sam wipes his ass with Charmin two-ply.
而山姆大叔正用昂貴品牌的衛生紙 擦拭著屁股呢
There was a 20 man.
當時圍了二十個人
Immigration gun was drawn.
入境室警衛的槍枝都拔了出來
The Dixon was ready to fire.
迪克遜準備要開槍
To kill the little man with the pills.
殺掉攜帶藥品的這小子
But then someone walks into the room and stand in front of this little man.
但後來有個人走進房裡 站在這小子的面前
"Put the guns away," the man say.
這個人說：「把槍放下」
"Nobody will die today. "
「今天沒人會死」
Who?
誰？
- Who was it that saved him? - Yeah, tell us. Who was it?
-是誰救了他？ -對，告訴我們是誰
Who was this man?
這個人是誰？
Navorski. Viktor "The Goat" Navorski.
納沃斯基，維克多"山羊"納沃斯基
- It doesn't look good, Frank. - I was just following the rules.
-情形不太樂觀，弗蘭克 -我只是遵照規則行事
Sometimes you have to ignore the rules and concentrate on the people.
有時候你得把規則撇到一邊 專注在人身上
The people, I know.
人，我懂
The people, compassion. That's the foundation of this country.
人民、同情 那是本國的基礎
You could learn something from Navorski.
你得向納沃斯基學習學習
Cheer up. It's not over yet.
高興點，還沒完呢
- Is that for me? - Yes. Yes.
-送我的嗎？ -是的
Is Virgin Isle swordfish.
是維京島旗魚
For you.
送你的
For wall.
掛在牆上
Fish for wall.
可掛牆上的魚
Why do you want to go to New York?
你為何想去紐約？
And what's in the can of peanuts?
罐子裡裝了什麼？
Promise.
承諾
- A promise in the can? - Yes. A promise.
-罐頭裡裝著承諾？ -對，一份承諾
Let me make you a promise, Viktor.
讓我為你立下一份承諾，維克多
And this is a promise that comes from a man who is stuck here.
一個困在這裡的人所做出的承諾
A man who may be stuck here for the next ten years.
可能還會再困個十年的人
From now on, you and I are partners.
從現在起，你和我是拍檔
If I stay, you stay.
若我留下，你就留下
You will not set one foot in New York City.
你一步也踏不進紐約市
Not a single toe in the United States of America.
一根腳趾頭也踏不進美國境內
Do you understand what I am saying to you?
聽懂我跟你說的話了嗎？
Yes.
我懂
You don't like fish.
你不喜歡魚
Do you ever feel like you're just living in an airport?
你覺不覺得你好像住在機場裡？
We don't have to do this, Viktor. I can ship you out in a crate.
我們不必這樣做，維克多 我可以把你裝進箱裡運出去
I can mail you anywhere in the US.
寄到美國任何地方
What about my food cart? He can hide inside and we'll drive out.
用我的運餐車怎樣？ 他可以躲在裡頭，我們再推出去
- No. I can't do this. - You said you wanted us to help you.
-不行，我不能這麼做 -你說過希望我們幫你的呀
- I do. - What's her name?
-是沒錯 -她叫什麼名字？
Amelia Warren.
艾米利亞·華倫
I thought we were looking for a way out, not a way in.
我以為我們是要找路出去 不是找路進來
Be careful. Those flight attendants ain't like regular women.
小心點，那些空姐不像一般女人
Flying back and forth between time zones messes with their biological clock.
在不同時差地區往返飛行 擾亂了她們的生理時鐘
- They're always ready for sex. - OK, I found something.
-她們隨時準備好發生性關係 -好的，我找到了點東西
I am leaving. They will come for us.
我要離開，他們會來找我們的
Gupta, will you relax? Just watch the door.
古普塔，你放鬆點好嗎？ 去門口把風
You go in jail. Not me.
會進監牢的是你們，不是我
For... You know what? Forget it.
為了…你知道嗎？ 算了
- Keep looking. - Warren, right?
-繼續找 -華倫 對吧？
- Yes. Yes. - Warren.
-沒錯 -華倫
Amelia Jane Warren?
艾米利亞 簡·華倫？
- Jane? - Yeah.
-簡？ -對
Way to go, Viktor. First class.
好極了，維克多，頭等艙
- When she come back? - Three weeks.
-她幾時回來？ -三週後
Amelia, would you like to get eat to bite?
艾米利亞，想去吃點東西嗎？
Bite to eat? Cantaloni?
吃點東西？肉餡卷？
Bite to eat?
吃點東西？
Eat to bite? Eat to bite.
點東西吃？點東西吃
Bite to eat.
吃點東西
Bite to eat. Bite to eat.
吃點東西，吃點東西
Bite to eat. Bite to eat. Bite to eat.
吃點東西，吃點東西，吃點東西
Bite to eat. Bite to eat. Bite to eat...
吃點東西，吃點東西，吃點東西…
Gupta, you been ever married?
古普塔，你結過婚嗎？
- What did you say? - You been ever married?
-你說什麼？ -你結過婚嗎？
I had a wife and two kids in India. I left them there 23 years ago.
我在印度有個老婆和兩個孩子 我在23年前丟下他們
Why?
為什麼？
I had a small tobacco shop in Madras.
我在馬德拉斯開了間小小菸草店
Made just enough money to survive.
勉強足以謀生
One day this policeman comes in and tells me I owe him some tax.
有一天，有個警察進來 說我欠他一些稅金
I said OK. This is common. So I pay him.
我說沒關係 這事稀鬆平常，所以就付給了他
The next day, the same policeman come and keep coming and keep coming.
隔天，同一個警察又來 三番兩次找上門來
And I am paying and I'm paying him and I'm paying him and I'm paying him.
我一直付錢給他，付個沒完沒了
And finally, on the fifth day, I take a knife and I stab him in his chest.
最後呢，在第五天 我拿起一把刀子刺進他的胸口
- You killed policeman? - No. I just missed his heart.
-你殺了警察？ -沒有，我沒刺中他的心臟
When they tried to arrest me, I run away.
當他想逮捕我時，我逃了
So you never go home?
那你沒回家嗎？
If I go home, I go in the jail for seven years.
我要是回家，就得在牢裡待上七年
What if United States catch you? They deport you.
萬一美國抓你的話呢？ 會把你驅逐出境
As long as I keep my floor clean, keep my head down,
只要我繼續把地板拖乾淨，保持低調
they have no reason to deport me.
他們就沒理由驅逐我
They have no reason to notice a man like me.
他們沒必要去注意像我這樣的人
United Airlines Flight 2703 from Rome is now arriving at Gate C43.
從羅馬來的美國航空2703號班機 現在抵達C43閘門
- Hey, wait. - Sorry. I'm sorry.
-嘿，等一下 -抱歉，真對不起
No, no, no. It's wet.
不准通行，地板濕的
- Hey. - Watch where you're going.
-嘿 -走路小心點
Watch out!
小心！
- Amelia. - Viktor.
-艾米利亞 -維克多
- Hello. - Sorry. I'm sorry.
-你好 -抱歉，真對不起
He nearly killed me.
他差點殺了我
- You OK? - I'm fine.
-你沒事吧？ -我很好
I love the suit.
穿這套西裝我喜歡
Hugo Boss.
雨果 波士品牌
On sale, $1 49.99.
特價149.99美元
That's a bargain.
真便宜
- Napoleon? - Yes, yes.
-拿破崙？ -沒錯
And Josephine.
還有約瑟芬呢
Do you know what Napoleon gave Josephine on their wedding day?
你知道他們結婚那一天 拿破崙送什麼給約瑟芬嗎？
Amelia?
艾米利亞？
Would you like to have eat to bite?
想去吃點東西嗎？
Food. Tonight?
食物，今晚？
- You're asking me out for dinner? - Yes.
-你在約我出去吃飯嗎？ -是的
Yeah. Sure.
當然好
- What time? - Dinnertime.
-幾點？ -晚餐時間
- Where do you want to go? - I know place.
-你想去哪吃？ -我知道個地方
- Do you have an appointment? - Navorski.
-你有預約嗎？ -納沃斯基
This way, please.
這邊請
Thank you.
謝謝
I didn't know they had a patio up here.
我不知道這上頭有個陽台呢
It's very nice.
非常不錯
Good night.
晚安
Please. Please. Please. Please.
拜託，拜託…
Sorry. So, tonight we have cannellonis or chicken.
抱歉，今晚要吃肉餡卷還是雞肉呢？
- Cannelloni, please. - Cannelloni.
-請來肉餡卷吧 -肉餡卷
- Sorry. - Thank you.
-抱歉 -謝謝
For you, sir?
你呢，先生？
- Same. - That's a great, great choice.
一樣吧 那是很棒很棒的選擇
I'll be back.
馬上就來
Let me see. Enjoy.
我想一下，請慢用
Did you know the croissant was invented in Romania?
你曉得羊角面包是羅馬尼亞發明的嗎？
- Tell me. - OK.
-說來聽聽 -好的
It's 1 7 42 and the Turks invade Bucharest,
1742年，土耳其人入侵布卡瑞斯特 (注: 羅馬尼亞首都)
making a surprise attack under the cover of night.
趁著月黑風高，出奇不意展開攻擊
But the town bakers...
但城裡的烤面包師…
Sorry.
抱歉
So, the bakers?
烤面包師怎樣呢？
- No, never mind. It's a dumb story. - No, please.
-算了，不說也罷，是個蠢故事 -不，請說
I'm sorry, Viktor.
對不起，維克多
Nobody really cares where the croissant was invented.
沒人真正在乎羊角面包是哪裡發明的
I'll bet the Romanians themselves don't give a shit.
我敢說羅馬尼亞人自己也不在乎
I care.
我在乎
Is histories. Is truth.
那是歷史，是事實
- I'm 39 years old. - No.
-我39歲了 -不
- Yeah.
-沒錯
- That's the truth. - You are not.
-那是事實 -你不像39了
I tell everybody I'm 33, and most of the men I've dated think I'm 27, but no.
我告訴大家我才33歲，和我約會過 的男人多半認為我才27歲，其實不是
I'm 39.
我39歲了
So? I was 39 once.
那又怎樣？ 我也曾經39歲過
I was 1 8 years old when I started working for the airlines.
我18歲就開始在航空公司服務
I've been doing this over 20 years.
我做這行已經超過20年了
And now there's no more pretending.
現在沒必要再假裝下去了
This is it.
就是這麼回事
It's why my address book is by city and my pager goes off during dinner.
所以我的通訊錄都在城市周圍 而我的傳呼機老在用餐時響起
You can switch off pager.
你可以把傳呼機關掉
I wish I could.
但願我能
I've been waiting for a phone call for seven years.
我一直在等一通電話 等了七年
I know it's coming, Viktor. That's why I can't break it off.
我知道快了，維克多 所以我才無法斬斷情絲
That's why I live out of hotels and have my little suitcase packed, ready to go,
所以我住在賓館裡 行李整理好，隨時準備離開
just in case he wants to meet me for the weekend.
以免他週末想要見我
Yeah.
沒錯
I've been waiting my whole life.
我一直等了一輩子
Just don't know what the hell for.
就是不明白究竟為什麼
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
I live here.
我住這裡
- What? - I live here, in terminal.
-什麼？ -我住這裡，就在候機室裡
Gate 67.
67號閘門
- You live at the airport? - Yes. Day and night.
-你住在機場？ -對，日日夜夜
This home, like you. They tell me to wait.
這個家，好比說你，都在叫我等待
So I wait.
所以我就等嘍
All frequent fliers feel the same way you do, Viktor.
所有經常搭機者 都跟你一樣感覺，維克多
Everybody's waiting. Everybody.
大家都在等待，大家都是
- For a flight, for a meeting... - I don't wait for flight or meeting.
-等著班機，等著會議… -我並沒在等班機或會議
Then what are you waiting for?
那你在等什麼？
Is OK. I understand.
沒關係，我瞭解
I have an idea.
我有個主意
- Come here. - What you do?
-過來 -你做什麼？
You sure?
你確定？
More than anything, I'm sure of this.
再確定不過了，我很確定
Ready?
準備好沒？
So, when do you come back?
那你幾時回來？
13 days. How about you?
13天後，你呢？
I will be here.
我會在這裡
But what if your schedule changes?
可是萬一你的行程改了呢？
Maybe we should exchange phone numbers.
也許我們該交換一下電話號碼
No. I will be here.
不用，我會在這裡
You know what Napoleon give to Josephine when he win Bavaria?
你知道拿破崙打敗巴伐利亞時 送給約瑟芬什麼東西嗎？
Tell me.
告訴我
Come on. Tell me.
別這樣嘛，告訴我
I will show you. 1 3 days from now.
13天後我會給你看的
What's he doing?
他在幹嘛？
I can't ask him. I'm supposed to tell him what he's doing.
我不問，我是應該跟他說他在幹嘛
If I ask him, I look like an idiot.
但果我問了，就像個白痴一樣
I'm sorry. Sorry. You got to do this for me.
對不起，你得替我做這件事
You'll get really fat with all the food I'm going to give you.
我會給你食物，多的讓你吃到發胖
But, please, do this for me. It will be the last thing I ask you to do.
拜託幫我做這事吧 這是我要求你的最後一件事
He waits for you to answer at Sbarro.
他在斯巴羅義式餐廳那裡等你回覆
- I have to work. - He will wait.
-我得工作 -他會等的
- How was your flight? - Good.
-旅途如何？ -還不錯
Thanks.
謝謝
- Is something wrong? - You'll have to come with us.
-有問題嗎？ -你必須跟我們來一趟
You're kidding. I come through here twice a month.
別開玩笑了，我一個月過境兩次呢
Please follow me.
請跟我走
I'm supposed to be meeting somebody.
有人等著見我呢
In my line of work, there are three things that matter.
我的工作，有三件重要事項
The person, the document and the story.
人、文檔和故事
Find the truth of one and you find the truth of all three.
找出其中一項的真相 就能找出這三項的真相
I need your help finding the truth.
我需要你幫忙找出真相
Do you know a man named Viktor Navorski?
你認識一個叫維克多·納沃斯基的人吧？
Yes.
是的
Do you know why he's here and where he's from?
你知道他為何在此及來自哪裡嗎？
No. We're just friends.
不知道，我們只是朋友而已
Have you noticed that he hides a can of Dry Roasted Peanuts in his bag?
你有注意到他背包裡藏了 一罐烘焙乾制的花生嗎？
So?
所以呢？
What do you make of that?
你會做成什麼呢？
I'd make peanut butter, I guess.
我大概會做成花生醬吧
We know that he's planning to go to the Ramada Inn on Lexington.
我們知道他計劃要去 列剋星敦的拉瑪達酒店
Has he told you why he's in New York?
他有跟你說過為何來紐約嗎？
No.
沒有
- Has he told you where he lives? - No. We just met at the airport.
-他有跟你說過他住哪嗎？ -沒有，我們只是在機場碰到的
All I know is that he's a building contractor, living out of a suitcase.
我只知道他是個建築承包商 整天帶著公文包
That's it.
就這樣子
- He's a contractor? - Yeah.
-他是個承包商？ -沒錯
That's what he said?
他就說那些嗎？
Amelia. I'm just curious.
艾米利亞，我只是很好奇
You are the kind of woman who can get any guy she wants.
你這種女人想要哪種男人都行
Why Viktor Navorski?
為何挑上維克多·納沃斯基呢？
That's something a guy like you could never understand.
那是你這種人永遠不會懂的事
I guess you missed your flight again. Or maybe you have a bad travel agent.
我猜你又錯過你的班機了 或者也許你的旅行社太差勁了
Please. Sit.
請坐
It's OK, Viktor. All men lie.
沒關係的，維克多，男人都會撒謊
- At least you're not very good at it. - I did not lie.
-至少你不是個中好手 -我沒撒謊
You told me you were delayed. You never said it was for nine months.
你告訴我你的班機延誤了 卻沒說延誤了九個月
Maybe you see the man the way you want see the man.
也許你是以你想看的方式 去看一個人
So what am I seeing? Who are you?
那我看見的是什麼？ 你是誰？
- I... - Unacceptable?
-我… -不受歡迎？
Yes. Yes.
是的，是的
You want to hear the funny part?
你想聽聽有趣的部分嗎？
I broke up with him.
我跟他分手了
I was coming here to tell you he's out of my life.
我是來此告訴你 他離開了我的生活
I'm free. I got tired of waiting.
我自由了，我厭倦了等待
At least we have that in common.
至少我們有著共同點
Amelia, you know what Napoleon give to Josephine when he win Bavaria?
艾米利亞，你知道拿破崙打敗巴伐利亞時 送給約瑟芬什麼東西嗎？
No.
不知道
I show you.
我帶你去看
Please. Please.
請，請
Sit. Please.
請坐
That was gift. Napoleon to Josephine.
那便是拿破崙送給約瑟芬的禮物
One thousand fountains.
一千個噴泉
You built this for me?
你為我蓋的？
Please. Sit. Don't get wet.
請坐，別弄濕了
Come on.
快點
Oh...
哦…
It no work.
沒作用
It should shoot, big water up to ceiling.
它應該往天花板噴出大量的水才對
Just tell me the truth. Did you escape from an institution?
跟我說實話 你是不是從瘋人院逃出來的？
Are you a criminal?
你是罪犯嗎？
You're living here, Viktor.
你住在這裡，維克多
You're living at Gate 67. I just want to know why.
你住在67號閘門，我只想知道原因
Here. I show you.
來，我給你看
My father.
我父親
Viktor, please tell me your father isn't in that peanut can.
維克多，請告訴我 花生罐裡裝的不是你父親
This is jazz.
這是爵士
My father, Dimitar Asenov Navorski,
我父親迪米特·阿森洛夫·納沃斯基
see this photograph in Hungarian newspaper 1 958.
在1958年匈牙利報上看到這張照片
He say he look at photograph for seven days.
他說他看著照片看了七天
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday...
週一、週二、週三…
Who are they?
他們是誰？
Count Basie, Dizzy Gillespie, Thelonious Monk, Sonny Rollins,
貝西伯爵、迪吉葛拉斯彼 塞隆尼斯孟克、桑尼羅林斯
Art Blakey, Max Kaminsky.
亞特布拉奇、麥克斯卡明斯基
57 of them all together.
總共57個
After looking at photograph for seven days, my father has idea.
他看著這些照片7天後，有個了主意
He begin to write letters to club, Lickety Split, Snookie's Sugar Bowl.
他開始給他們寫信
He ask the nuns to write English. Hundreds letters.
他央求修女幫他寫英文信，好幾百封
And then he wait.
然後他就等
He wait month, week, year.
一個月、一週、一年
My father wait 40 year.
我父親等了40年
And they all sign names.
他們都簽了名
One by one.
一個一個
They all write their name and send it to my father.
他們都簽了名寄給我父親
All but not one.
除了一個
Benny Golson.
班尼高森
Saxophone.
薩克斯手
My father die before Benny Golson write his name and send to my father.
我父親在得到班尼高森 的簽名之前就去世了
So I make him promise. I keep promise.
我為了完成他的遺願 我遵守諾言
I promise I will go New York, find Benny Golson,
我保證要到紐約找到班尼高森
have him write name to put in can.
得到他的簽名放到罐子裡面
And you've been living here so you could do this for your father?
你住在這裡就是為了幫你父親得到簽名？
Maybe I think he do it for me.
也許是他在幫我
You say you are waiting for something.
你說過你在等待
And I say to you, "Yes, yes. We all wait".
我對你說，"是的，我們都在等待"
What are you waiting for?
你在等什麼？
You. I wait for you.
你，我在等你
What?
怎麼了？
The war is over.
戰爭結束了
...the right-wing military coup that ousted President Vagobagin...
…驅逐瓦果巴金的右翼武裝…
All right, everybody. Let's raise your glasses.
各位，讓我們舉杯
Let's have a toast to my friend, Viktor "The Goat".
為我們的朋友「山羊」維克多乾杯
May he never lose his country again.
祝他永遠不會再次失去祖國
Krakozhia!
克羅西亞！
Amelia! You here early!
艾米利亞！ 你來早了！
Hello. Amelia, look.
艾米利亞，看啊
Peace, peace in the war. The war, peace. Come.
和平…戰爭…結束了，和平…來了
See, the war, the war Krakozhia is over.
克羅西亞內戰結束了
Peace. The war is over.
和平，戰爭結束了
- You know my friend in Washington. - Yes, yes.
- 你知道我在華府的那個朋友嗎？ - 知道，知道
He has a lot of connections. Here.
他在那裡很有些門路
It's a pass, Viktor.
通行證，維克多
A one-day travel emergency visa with your name on it.
寫有你名字的一天緊急簽證
- Wha... Visa? - Yes.
- …簽證？ - 是的
- From your friend? - Yeah.
- 你朋友給的？
Just go to New York, find that last name and put it in the can.
去紐約，拿到最後一個簽名，放到罐子裡面吧
- I go New York? - Yes.
- 我，去紐約？ - 是的
I go New York!
我可以去紐約了！
Amelia, you come with. You come with me to New York.
艾米利亞，你跟我，跟我一起去紐約
Your friend do this for me? Why he do this for me?
你朋友幫我的？ 他為什麼要幫我？
He did it for me.
他是幫我
I told you to stay away from me, Viktor. But you didn't understand.
我讓你遠離我，維克多 但你不明白
- I think you were confused. - No, I confused about everything.
- 我想你沒弄明白 - 不，不，很多事情我不明白
I not confused... Not this. Not this.
但這件事，不是的…
I'm sorry. I'm running late.
抱歉，我要遲到了
Amelia. Why you go? Why you go?
艾米利亞，為什麼要走？ 為什麼要走？
You know what Napoleon gave Josephine as a wedding present?
你知道拿破崙給了約瑟芬什麼結婚禮物嗎？
It was a gold locket.
是一個金匣子
And on the inside, he made an inscription.
他在裡面刻了字
"Destiny".
"命運"
Destiny.
命運
...rejoice in the streets as well as in their local taverns.
…在街上和酒館裡表達喜悅之情
The Krakozhian flag waved goodbye from high atop the parliament buildings.
遠處的克羅西亞國旗在議會大廈樓頂揮手作別
It is a clear sign of the power...
這清楚表明…
- Hey, baby. - Hi.
- 嘿，寶貝 - 嗨
I missed you.
我想你
Come on.
走吧
Next.
下一個
Viktor.
維克多
Hello, Delores. How I am today?
你好，德洛蕾絲，我今天有希望嗎？
What do you have here?
你今天有什麼？
Oh, no. It's not signed.
哦，不，沒有簽字
What?
什麼？
This is a one-day emergency travel visa.
這是張一天緊急旅遊簽證
To validate authenticity, it needs to be signed by the supervising officer.
必須由管理官員簽字才能生效
Dixon?
迪克遜？
Yes.
是的
Dixon.
迪克遜
The war in my country is over.
我的國家戰爭已經結束
Yeah. I know. Congratulations.
我知道，祝賀你
It's strange, isn't it, Viktor?
很奇怪吧，維克多？
When you wait so long for one thing?
你為一件事情等了那麼長時間？
One tiny moment.
就在那一瞬間
I had that moment today, too.
我今天也是如此
You see this badge?
你看見這個徽章了？
This badge means that I was made CBP Field Commissioner.
我現在是邊境局的地區特派員了
It means that my authority over the security of this airport is absolute.
我現在對機場的保安有絕對控制權
Your ticket and your passport.
你的機票和護照
It's time for you to go home.
你可以回家了
Officer Waylin, please show Mr. Navorski into the terminal
威靈警官，送納沃斯基先生去候機廳
and make sure he does not miss his flight.
確保他別誤了飛機
Goodbye, Viktor, and good luck.
再見，維克多，祝好運
I think I want go New York City.
我要去紐約
Don't make this difficult, Viktor.
別再惹麻煩了，維克多
I no more "unacceptable".
我不再是 "不受歡迎了"
- I told you this is over. - I go New York.
- 我告訴你都結束了 - 我，要去紐約
Are you sure you want to do that?
你說真的？
I go New York City now.
我，要去紐約
Part of my job is to get rid of undesirables, and there are quite a few.
我的工作就是驅逐那些不受歡迎的人 這裡就有幾個
Like this guy, Joe Mulroy. I think you know him.
這個傢伙，喬·瑪洛伊 我想你認識他
He's been here for 20 years, but he's been running an after-hour poker game.
他在這兒工作已經20年了，但他下班後在機場賭博
Bringing in liquor and marijuana.
還帶來酒和大麻
Poor guy's going to lose his pension. And I think he has kids, too.
可憐的傢伙會失去退休金，他有孩子的吧
Yep.
是的
And then there's this guy, Enrique Cruz. I think you also know Enrique.
這個傢伙，恩裡剋剋魯茲 你也認識吧
Enrique has been letting people into the food preparation area.
恩裡克讓外人進入廚房
That's a major security breach.
這嚴重違反安全條例
The poor guy, I think he's a newlywed.
可憐的傢伙，他剛結婚吧
But I'm going to have to let him go.
但我會放過他
And then there's Gupta Rajan. He's a janitor.
然後是古普塔·拉金 他是清潔工
But he's wanted for assaulting a police officer back in India in 1 979.
但他1979年在印度因為襲警而被通緝
I'll have to deport him.
我得遣返他
I will go home.
我回家
- I'm sorry. What did you say? - I will go home.
- 你說什麼？ - 我回家
Leave them alone. I will go.
別動他們，我回家
- Today. - Yes.
- 今天 - 是的
If you don't get on that plane, they're all gone.
如果你不上飛機，他們就全部完蛋
- Do you understand? - Yes.
- 你明白嗎？ - 是的
OK. Good.
很好
Your attention please.
請注意
Immediate boarding, gate B-20, for flight number 309 Air Canada to Ottawa.
搭乘加拿大航空往渥太華309號班機 的旅客,請立即到B-20閘門登機
I don't believe you.
我不相信你
- Viktor, you don't have to do this. - You can fight these guys.
-維克多，你不必這樣妥協 -你可以打倒這些傢伙
- We'll help you. - Viktor, come on. I owe you so much.
-我們會幫你的 -維克多，別這樣，我欠你太多了
- Please let me help you. - This is your friend talking.
-拜託讓我幫你 -這是朋友的勸告
We're all your friends. We're your family now.
我們全是你的朋友 現在和你是一家人了
Gupta.
古普塔
Goodbye.
再見
You try to fool us.
你想戲弄我們
You make us to think you would walk out, that you will fight with them.
你令我們認為你會走出去 你會挺身對抗他們
Why don't you fight?
你為何不反擊？
- The war is over. - Then go. Get lost.
-戰爭結束了 -那就走吧，滾蛋
Get lost. Go home and tell them you never made it.
滾開，回家去告訴他們你辦不到
You come this close to America,
你離美國這麼近了
but you don't have the courage to go from here to here.
但你沒勇氣從這裡走到那裡
You are a coward.
你是懦夫
The plane is on time.
搭機時間到了
You are a coward!
你是懦夫！
You make me sick!
你令我噁心！
What's wrong with you, man? Settle down.
你有毛病啊，老兄？鎮靜點
Got people looking all around, looking at me like I'm...
周圍的人都在看呢 看著我，好像我是…
Look at me.
看著我
Come on, look at me.
快點，看著我
There's something you should know.
有些事情我要告訴你
Ladies and gentlemen, United Airlines Flight 865
先生們女士們，聯航從克羅西亞來的
from Krakozhia has landed and is now taxiing to the gate.
865航班已經降落，正往閘口開來
For those passengers holding tickets for Flight 866 to Krakozhia,
持有去克羅西亞的866航班機票的旅客
we expect departure to be on schedule.
希望你們如期出發
Get back, please.
請退後
Gupta.
古普塔
Gupta!
古普塔！
I am going home.
我回家了
Get lost.
走吧
Your attention, please.
請注意
Flight 866 to Krakozhia will be delayed until further notice.
飛往克羅西亞的866航班 將推遲起飛，等候進一步通知
Do you have an appointment?
你們有預約嗎？
Somebody tell me what the hell is going on down there!
誰告訴我下面到底是他媽的怎麼回事！
We're right behind you.
我們支持你
Viktor's leaving.
維克多要走了
- Monica, Viktor's leaving. - I know. He's going home.
- 莫尼卡，維克多要走了 - 我知道，他回家
He's going for the front door, out to the city.
他朝前門走了，要到市區去
What?
什麼？
Viktor. Remember us.
維克多，別忘了我們
From the Discovery Store, I want to give you this.
我是探索書店的，拿著這個
It's good luck.
會給你好運的
A digital camera for cousin Katia.
給我表妹卡蒂亞帶的數碼相機
I don't know where you're going, but these will keep your feet warm.
我不知道你要去哪兒，這個可以給你暖腳
- Everybody in position? - We're here.
- 大家都在崗位嗎？ - 是的
Secure the door.
守好門口
Sorry, Viktor.
抱歉，維克多
Take him, Judge.
抓住他，賈吉
Hold it, Viktor. Take it easy.
等等，維克多，別激動
You see those doors?
看見這些門了？
Those are the entry doors to New York City.
他們是去紐約的入口
To the United States of America. Turn around.
去美國的入口，轉過身
It's snowing in the city and you're going to need that.
外面在下雪，你會需要的
Good luck.
好運
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no.
哦，不，不，不
I'm going to miss you.
我會想你的
Try not to get stuck wherever you're going.
別再被困在別的地方了
Arrest him! Arrest him!
逮捕他，逮捕他！
Goddammit!
該死！
Taxi!
出租車！
Thank you.
謝謝
Where you go?
去哪兒？
1 61 Lexington. Please take Van Wyck Expressway to Queensboro Bridge.
列剋星敦街161號，走范懷克高速到皇后大橋
It's faster than BQE.
比BQE高速要快
- Where you from? - Krakozhia. Viktor Navorski.
- 你打哪兒來？ - 克羅西亞…維克多·納沃斯基
I'm Goran. Albania.
我是格蘭，阿爾巴尼亞人
- When do you come to New York? - Thursday.
- 你什麼時候到紐約的？ - 星期二
You want us to block the south exit and have AP sweep every vehicle?
你要封鎖南邊出口，檢查每輛車嗎？
Sir?
先生？
5.30 from Tokyo just landed.
…從東京來的飛機剛剛降落
Got two planes on the tarmac. Barcelona on approach.
停機坪上還有兩架飛機，巴塞羅那的也要到了
The night is young and 1 500 people are headed our way.
時間還早，還有1500名旅客要抵達
Everybody inside.
都進去吧，進去吧
Come on, let's go.
快，走吧
Let's go.
走吧
- Are you checking in, sir? - No, no. I don't check in.
- 你要入住嗎，先生？ - 不，不了
I want to go to this place, please.
我要到這個地方
The lobby lounge is around the corner.
哦，就在拐角處
They have happy hour specials and live music. Do you like jazz?
那裡有一小時現場音樂會，你喜歡爵士樂嗎？
The monitor's off.
關掉揚聲器
The piano's OK. A little more bass. More bass from the monitor.
鋼琴沒問題，再來點低音
Let's do Killer Joe. It worked all right last night.
我們演奏「殺手喬」，昨天效果不錯
- Yes? - You are Benny Golson?
- 嗯？ - 你是班尼高森？
Yeah. Yes, I am.
是的，我是
Benny Golson, I am Viktor Navorski. I am from Krakozhia.
班尼高森，我是維克多·納沃斯基 從克羅西亞來
My father, Dimitar Asenov Navorski, was great, great fan of your music.
我父親，迪米特·阿森洛夫·納沃斯基 是你的超級樂迷
A jazz fan. Fantastic.
爵士迷，太好了
Would you sign your name, please?
能簽個名嗎？
Can I do it a little later? We have to get started now.
能等會兒嗎？我們就要開始了
- Just a minute. - I will wait.
- 稍等 - 我會等的
OK.
好
Taxi! Taxi!
出租車！出租車！
Where you want to go?
你要去哪兒？
I am going home.
回家